In this video, we're going to look at
creating a payables transaction in
Dynamics SL and compare that to the
experience of entering a payables
transaction in Dynamics 365 Business
Central.
In Dynamics SL, I'll create an AP
voucher for some office supplies that we
had purchased from one of our vendors.
In voucher and adjustment, I'll enter
the vendor information,
the vendor invoice number,
and then the purchase amount for the
supplies.
Save and release the batch.
Now, let's explore how we can enter the
same transaction in Business Central.
In Business Central, you can use the
purchase journal or purchase invoices to
register the cost of purchases and track
accounts payable.
Purchase journals can be used to
register expenses for those you may not
track in inventory.
Purchase invoices can be used to track
purchases of inventoried items as well
as non-inventoried items.
To create payable transactions, search
for purchase journals and choose the
purchase journal link in the search
result.
Enter the vendor invoice number just
like I did in SL.
And now I will select my vendor.
Next, I can enter in my purchase amount
and select my office supply GL account.
Before closing my transaction, I can see
a preview of the GL accounts the
transaction will be posted to.
Now, let's look at entering in a
purchase invoice.
To create a purchase invoice, we'll go
ahead and select purchasing from the
role center menu
and then select purchase invoices.
Next, choose new to create the invoice.
The first thing to do is choose the
vendor that we are purchasing these
supplies from.
After selecting the vendor, you can see
the vendor information has defaulted in
from the vendor record.
Next, we will record the vendor invoice
number.
Now, we can add the lines to the
purchase invoice.
If we're wanting to register purchases
for services or items not found in
inventory, we can select the GL account
and in this example, select our supplies
account, then the purchase amount.
Because the purchase invoice allow for
multiple types, we can also enter the
lines for inventory items, fixed assets,
or track any freight expenses we may
have occurred.
Using purchase journals and or purchase
invoices, this is central provides
additional flexibility when capturing
your business expenses.
To learn more about Business Central,
see the following resources.